CARLOS A. BLANCO V.

Madrid, Spain | +34 641 65 85 28 | karlosblanco000@gmail.com

Summary

A Systems Engineer graduated in 2011, with more than 8 years of experience in software development, since 2014 specializing in the development of Android applications, I like to create applications with usable and intuitive interfaces. I also know the importance of creating software with ease of use. read and maintain your source code. I'm always willing to learn new technologies and share my knowledge, implementing best practices and always looking to become a better professional.

Skills

Kotlin	Java	Room	Android SDK	Facebook SDK
Linux	Android Studio	Retrofit	Git	Google Services
Huawei Mobile Services	Memory management	Push notification	Firebase services	Design Patterns
Dependency injection	Android Architecture Components	Clean Architecture	Flutter	Dart
Scrum				

Experience

Software Engineer Android @mo2o

Date: November 2021 - Currently work here

- I work as a team member in differents projects, with kotlin, java, mvp and mvvm, I has been develop projects with compose too building interface with this new technology
- I'm working on several projects from different areas, implementing the latest blocking technologies, external libraries and third-party SDKs for their development
- I also collaborate with the company giving ideas of possible solutions to new clients or what can be offered on a mobile level with the Android operating system.
- I collaborate with my colleagues on other projects as well as weekly meetings to share knowledge and see some new technology that has come out.

Software Engineer Android @ PedidosYa

Date: September 2021 - November 2021

- Develop and maintenance of the Fintech Module, the module is integrated with the core app, serving to checkout, as wallet and other features associated with the fintech module.
- Participate and contribute in cell meetings, this is to share knowledge and help to improve Android Skills of the team or share to other team members.

Lead Architect @ Everis Peru

Date: September 2020 - August 2021

- Developer and manager of the Android team on behalf of Everis of the Interbank App, helping to make technical decisions regarding Android and its environment
- Develop an external library that is directly integrated into the bank's main app, using the Scrum methodology during its development, built 100% in kotlin using an MVVM, Singleton, Factory, Observer, among others.
- I participate and contribute to leading the mobile knowledge group within everis, where together
 with my colleagues we share about new technologies and best practices of mobile
 development, with Android, iOS and hybrid, also by contributing to the leadership of the group,
 organized the sessions and topics, using tools such as: trello, mural and among other tools to
 carry the knowledge group sessions and make them much more dynamic.

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, mvvm con architecture component, Room, LiveData, ViewModel, WorkManager, Flow, Coroutines, FirebaseProducts, MatomoAnalitycs, huawei mobile services, creation and implementation of libraries with .aar files, dynamic features, Scrum.

Solutions Specific Knowledge Analyst @ Everis Peru

Date: Junio 2019 - Septiembre 2020

- Android developer in the Interbank client
- I have worked on the development of an external library that is directly integrated into the bank's main app, using the Scrum methodology during its development
- He participated in the mobile knowledge group within everis, where together with my colleagues
 we shared about new technologies and best practices of mobile development, with Android, iOS
 and hybrid.

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, mvvm con architecture component, Room, LiveData, ViewModel, WorkManager, Flow, Coroutines, FirebaseProducts, MatomoAnalitycs, huawei mobile services, creation and implementation of libraries with .aar files, dynamic features, Scrum.

Senior Android developer @ Peruapps

Date: Enero 2019 - Junio 2019

- Leader of the Android development team, during this I monitor the projects, management and development of new features and everything related to the Android team.
- Trabajé directamente en aplicativos e iniciativas tales como Caja Arequipa (App destinada a transacciones bancarias), Falabella (Aplicativo retail), Mitsubishi (aplicativo automotriz) y entre otros aplicativos de diferentes áreas.
- I worked directly on applications and initiatives such as Caja Arequipa (App for banking transactions), Falabella (Retail application), Mitsubishi (automotive application) and among other applications from different areas.
- He made technical decisions about the direction of all projects and helped managers and salespeople in the integration of new projects, forming part of the team that would meet with clients.

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, JSON, Realm, patrón mvp, mvc.

Senior Android developer @ Novategica

Date: Septiembre 2018 - Diciembre 2018

Work by project contract for the development of an electronic invoicing app, it is with the one currently invoiced by the LIMA GAS company, with it you can print sales tickets ticket / invoice with its direct issuance to the SUNAT (National Superintendency of Customs and Tax administration).

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, JSON, Realm, EPSON SDK and implementation Paperless(software to connect with the tributes government agency), Sockets, Bluetooth-

Senior Android developer @ Diloo

Date: Junio 2018 - Septiembre 2018

In Diloop I worked as a developer and manager of the Android platform, I worked closely with the backend and marketing team to develop the new app that would be used for this company, implement new features such as the shopping cart, separate by category, consumption of multiple services through JSON API and cloud services such as Firebase. Collaborate closely with the creative and management team in making decisions, the result of my work helped increase the user and income of the startup.

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, JSON, Firebase, Node.js, TypeScript, Google maps

Senior Android developer @ PeruApps

Date: Agosto 2017 - Junio 2018

Developer of multiple Android apps for the company's clients, such as Teoma, GiftCard Xpress and O2 Medical network and others that are not published since they were internal management of companies like Proyecta, in addition to developing internal tools for the company.

Relevant technologies: Java, Kotlin, Android SDK, Volley, MVP, retrofit, firebase product, google maps, tracking y sequimiento.

Android developer @ Develop

Date: Enero 2017 - Agosto 2017

During my time working with Develop (Spain) I was able to contribute to the development of applications such as Visecurity which served to track staff using geolocation with google, also upload incidents to the server both offline and online, among other apps for the areas.

Android developer @ Freelancer

Date: Desde 2014 con Android

I have worked on different projects with different characteristics, some projects that I can mention such as the series of apps for a client in Argentina and the range of Chivilcoy apps that go from apps to publish places to visit to apps to show relevant news about the city of Chivilcoy, Argentina, I like to do proofs of concept testing new technologies and seeing their advantages and disadvantages.

Education

Universidad de Margarita El valle, Porlamar, Venezuela System Engineer, 2011